( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( SCREAMING )
( ALARM CLOCK BEEPING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( BEEPING STOPS )
Claire .
( SIGHS )
I miss you .
( WATER DRIPPING )
STARCK : Dr. Weir ,
report to the Lewis Clark in docking bay four .
( ENGINES BLASTING )
JUSTIN : Ion drive set .
SMITH : Thank you .
( COMPUTER KEYS CLACKING )
Heading , Vector One , nine degrees .
We are prepped for lock down .
( BEEPS )
I can 't believe it , this is ridiculous .
I haven 't got more than my hand in the last six weeks ,
and now this shit .
I mean , why can 't we go to Mars , Captain ?
I mean , Mars has got women .
Smith 's right .
Neptune , there 's nothing out there .
SMITH : Yeah , and if the shit goes down , we 'll be on our own .
You know the rules , people .
Someone drops the ball , we get the call .
Now , let 's go .
Have you got our course plotted in ? Yes , sir .
Locked and cocked and ready to rock .
Mr. Justin ?
Everything 's green on my screen , Skipper .
MILLER : Start your countdown now .
Ion drive will engage in T minus 10 minutes .
Thank you , Lieutenant .
Let 's go . Smith , you follow me .
SMITH : Yes , ma 'am .
MILLER : Justin , get those tanks prepped .
JUSTIN : Yes , sir .
Mr. Cooper . COOPER : Skipper .
Ion drive in 10 minutes .
Ooh , it 's time to play spam-in-the-can .
Skipper . MILLER : Peters .
Captain Miller , I just wanted to say this is something ...
Clock is ticking , Doctor .
You waiting for a personal invitation , there , Mr. Smith ?
No , sir . Captain , I don 't want to take up any ...
Doctor , if you 'll just follow the rest of the crew to the grav tanks ,
we 're almost underway .
That bunk better be squared away , Mr. Cooper ,
or you 'll find yourself walking to Neptune .
What 's the hold-up , Peters ?
Just loading the last of the 002 scrubbers , sir .
You stand right here .
SMITH : Thanks , D.J.
SMITH : Hats off in the tank . Sir .
First time in a grav couch ?
Yeah . Uh-huh .
I think your captain has some kind of a problem with me .
Oh , well . Don 't worry about him .
He just loves having complete strangers on his ship .
D.J. D.J. Yeah .
No .
Is this necessary ?
When the ion drive fires ,
you 'll be taking about 30 G 's .
( GROANING ) Without a tank ,
the force would liquefy your skeleton .
I 've seen the effect on mice .
Claustrophobic ?
Very . Hmm .
CLAIRE : Billy .
I 'm so alone .
Hello ?
Is anyone there ?
Oh , God .
CLAIRE : Billy ?
I 'm so cold .
Claire .
I 'm waiting .
( SCREAMING )
( COUGHING ) You 're all right . Breathe .
D.J. !
Okay , Dr. Weir , let 's get you up . Okay , I 'm fine .
Come on , take it easy . I 'm fine .
Okay . There you go .
Now move nice and slow .
You 've been in stasis for 56 days .
You 're gonna experience a little disorientation , you understand ?
I 'm all right now , thank you .
( LAUGHING ) Okay , take that . Don 't rush it .
All yours .
( COUGHING )
You okay , Doc ?
Want some coffee ?
What ?
Would you like some coffee ?
No . Thank you .
All right , suit yourself .
What about you , STARCK ?
Would you like something hot and black inside you ?
Ooh ! Is that an offer ?
It is not .
Then how about some coffee , then ?
STARCK ? Oh .
Yes , sir . Why aren 't you on the bridge ?
Do you mind if I get dressed first ?
As a matter of fact , Lieutenant ,
I do mind if you get dressed first .
Let 's go , people . We have a job to do .
PETERS : Okay , Denny , here we go .
Happy birthday .
Play horsey , Mommy . Play horsey .
( EXCLAIMING ) Hey , no more ball in the house .
COOPER : Sorry , Mama .
JUSTIN : Yeah , you 're the one who can 't catch .
COOPER : Yo , apologize .
( LAUGHING ) Sorry about that , mama bean
All right . All right , then .
MILLER : Uh , Peters . Yes , sir .
I did try to find a replacement for you ,
but with such short notice , it was impossible .
I am sorry .
I talked to my ex .
He 's going to take Denny for Christmas .
I 'll get him for the summer ,
so everything 's all right .
COOPER : Smitty .
Excuse me , ladies and gentlemen ,
in approximately two hours and 23 minutes ,
we 'll be arriving in the orbit of Neptune .
Thank you very much . I thank you .
Ooh , that 's good .
All boards are green . Everything 's five by five .
USAC been notified of our position ?
STARCK : Yes , sir .
All right , people , listen up . SMITH : D.J.
MILLER : As you all know , we have an addition to our crew .
Dr. Weir , you care to join us ?
Introductions all around .
This is my XO , Lieutenant STARCK .
Mr. Justin , engineering .
The funky spaceman over here is Mr. Cooper .
What exactly is it you do on board this ship , Coop ?
Listen up , Doc , I 'm your best friend , okay ?
I am the lifesaver and the heart breaker .
He 's a rescue technician .
This is Peters , medical technician .
And my pilot , Mr. Smith .
The gloomy Gus in the corner over there , that 's ...
D.J. Trauma .
( ALL LAUGHING )
COOPER : All right , all right .
Now that we all know each other ,
Skipper , I got a question . MILLER : Certainly .
What the fuck are we doing way out here ?
Well , perhaps the good doctor will be kind enough to tell us .
Thank you . Uh ... ( CLEARING THROAT )
First of all , I want to say how much I appreciate
this opportunity to join you on what I ...
It 's for sure that you appreciate being here , Doctor ,
but you must understand that we don 't .
We were taken off a well-deserved leave
and sent into Neptune space .
We are now three billion klicks from the nearest outpost .
The last time USAC attempted a rescue
this far past the outer reach ,
well , we lost both ships . 80 , if you please ...
Right . Well ...
Everything I 'm about to tell you is considered Code Black by the NSA .
USAC intercepted a radio transmission
from a decaying orbit around Neptune .
The source of this transmission has been identified
as the Event Horizon .
Yeah , well , that 's bullshit , for starters .
Skipper , you took me off leave ...
( ALL CHATTERING ) Thank you so much .
Smitty , sit down .
Cooper , as you were .
Let the man speak .
WEIR : What was made public about the Event Horizon ,
that she was a deep space research vessel ,
that her reactor went critical ,
and that the ship blew up ,
none of that is true .
The Event Horizon was the culmination
of a secret government project to create a spacecraft
capable of faster-than-light flight .
SMITH : I don 't ... Excuse me .
See , you can 't actually do that .
The law of relativity prohibits faster-than-light travel .
Relativity , yes . We can 't break the law of relativity .
We can go around it .
The ship doesn 't really go faster than light .
What it does is it creates a dimensional gateway ,
that allows it to jump instantaneously
from one point of the universe to another light years away .
How ?
Well , it 's ... It 's difficult to ... It 's all math .
Try us , Doctor .
Right , well , uh , using layman 's terms ,
we use a rotating magnetic field
to focus a narrow beam of gravitons .
These in turn fold space-time
consistent with Weyl tensor dynamics ,
until the space-time curvature becomes infinitely large
and you produce a singularity . Now , the singularity ...
Layman 's terms .
Well , fuck layman 's terms . Do you speak English ?
Um ...
Imagine , for a minute , that this piece of paper ...
Excuse me . Uh , that 's Vanessa , and that 's mine . Uh ...
Attractive piece of paper represents space-time ,
and you want to get from point " A " here ...
Oh ... To point " B " there .
Now , what 's the shortest distance between two points ?
A straight line .
( MEN LAUGHING )
Wrong .
The shortest distance between two points is zero .
And that 's what the gateway does .
It folds space ,
so that point " A " and point " B " co-exist in the same space and time .
When the spacecraft passes through the gateway ,
space returns to normal .
It 's called a gravity drive .
JUSTIN : How do you know all this ?
I built it .
Well , I can see why they sent you .
So if the ship didn 't blow up , then what happened ?
Well , the mission was going perfectly , like a textbook .
They reached safe distance using conventional thrusters .
All systems looked good .
They had the go-ahead to use the gravity drive
to open the gateway to Proxima Centauri ,
and then , they just disappeared .
Vanished without a trace , until now .
Where 's she been for the last seven years , Doctor ?
That 's what we 're here to find out .
Now , we 've been unable to verify live contact ,
but TDRS did receive this single transmission .
( PLAYS RECORDING )
( SCREAMING )
( CREATURE ROARING )
( RECORDING STOPS )
What the fucking hell is that ?
Listen to this .
Houston passed the same recording through several filters ,
managed to isolate what appears to be a human voice .
( MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON RECORDING )
I 'm not even sure if it qualifies as language .
Latin . What ?
I mean , I think it sounds like Latin .
Can you translate it ?
Play it again .
( MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
Right there . You hear that ?
Sounds like , " liberate me , "
something . I don 't know . I can 't make out the rest .
" Liberate me ? "
" Save me . "
( ALARM BUZZING )
MILLER : All right . Stations , people .
Crossing the horizon .
Optimum approach angle is 14 degrees .
MILLER : Come around to 334 .
Heading 334 , sir .
Make your approach vector negative , 14 degrees .
1-4 degrees .
We have a lock on Event Horizon 's navigation beacon .
She 's in the upper ionosphere and it looks like ...
( THUDDING ) ... we 're in for some very heavy chop , sir .
Bring us in nice and tight , Mr. Smith . Sir .
Mr. Justin , how 's my ship ?
Smooth sailing , sir .
Matching speed on my mark .
Three , two , one . Mark .
Range ?
10,000 meters and closing , sir .
MILLER : STARCK . STARCK : Yes , sir .
Get on the horn . See if anybody is listening .
This is the US . Aerospace command vessel Lewis Clark
hailing Event Horizon .
Event Horizon , do you read ?
MILLER : Dr. Weir .
I think you 'll want to see this .
Where is she ?
Dead ahead . 5,000 meters !
STARCK ? Anybody home ?
Event Horizon , do you read ?
3,000 meters and closing !
I can 't see a thing .
1,500 meters , sir . We 're getting too close .
Where is it ?
The scope is lit . It 's right in front of us .
( ALARM BLARING ) 1,000 meters .
Proximity warning !
900 , 800 , 700 .
We 're right on top of her , sir ! MILLER : We 're gonna hit .
STARCK ! It 's right there ! God !
Reverse thrusters . Full !
( ALARM CONTINUES BLARING )
There she is .
JUSTIN : Jesus .
Very impressive ship , Doctor .
Thank you .
Mr. Smith , are you up for a flyby ?
Yes , sir . Yes , I 'd love to .
That 's the main airlock , we can dock in there .
All right , Smith .
Use the arm and lock us onto that small antenna cluster .
( MOTOR WHIRRING )
We should go very carefully here .
That is not a load-bearing structure .
Is now , Doctor .
Everything five by five ?
Locked in to the Event Horizon .
Thank you , Smitty . Light ' em if you got ' em .
Thank you very much , sir .
STARCK , give me a read .
The reactor 's still hot .
Uh , we 've got several small radiation sources but no leaks .
( BEEPING ) Probably it 's nothing serious .
MILLER : Do they have pressure ? Affirmative .
The hull 's intact , uh , but there 's no gravity ,
and the thermal units are off-line .
I 'm showing deep cold .
The crew couldn 't survive unless they were in stasis .
Find ' em , STARCK .
Yeah , I 'm already on it , Captain . Bio-scan is on the line .
There 's something wrong with the scan .
Is it radiation interference ?
STARCK : There 's not enough to throw it off .
I 'm picking up trace life forms ,
but I can 't get a lock on their location .
These readings are all over the ship . It doesn 't make any sense .
Okay , we do it the hard way . Deck by deck , room by room .
STARCK , deploy the umbilicus .
Smitty , fire up the boards in the war room .
Sir .
Mr. Justin , I believe you 're up for a walk ?
Yes , sir .
Doctor , I 'm gonna need you here on the bridge .
Captain , I didn 't come out all this way just to sit on your bridge .
I need to be on that ship .
Once we 've secured the ship , we 'll bring you on board .
No , I 'm sorry , that 's unacceptable . I need to be on that ship .
Once we 've secured the ship . That 's the way it is .
I need you to guide us from the com station .
This is where I need you .
Help us do our job .
Oh , oh , oh ! Honey , honey , you forgot your briefcase .
Stand clear .
Anything gets funky , Cooper ...
I 'll be on it .
Yo , baby bear , keep your nose clean .
D.J. , showtime .
Video feed is clear .
Are you with us , Dr. Weir ?
Yes , I 'm ... I 'm with you .
MILLER : We are crossing the umbilicus ,
making our approach to the Event Horizon .
You 're at the outer airlock door .
( BEEPS )
MILLER : Magnetic boots on .
PETERS : We 've got pressure .
MILLER : Place is a deep freeze .
We got ice crystals everywhere .
That 's the central corridor that you 're in now .
It connects the personnel areas at the front of the ship
to engineering at the rear .
MILLER : Mr. Justin , you take engineering .
JUSTIN : Yes , sir .
MILLER : Peters and I 'll take the forward decks .
( BEEPING )
MILLER : Doctor , what are these ?
PETERS : Yeah , I 've got another one over here .
They are all over the place .
In an emergency ,
they destroy the central corridor and split the ship in half ,
and then the crew can use the foredecks as a lifeboat .
MILLER : I 'm in medical . No casualties .
Place looks like it 's never been used .
WEIR : You still haven 't seen any crew ?
If we saw any crew , Doctor , you 'd know it by now .
Scanning for life readings .
This place is a tomb .
Oh ! Fuck me !
( GASPING )
STARCK : Miller . Miller , are you okay ?
Looks like Skipper got a case of the willies .
STARCK : Cooper , get back to your post .
Miller , your heart rate just went through the roof .
I 'm fine .
( SIGHING )
JUSTIN : I think I 've reached the door
to the first containment , Dr. Weir .
WEIR : The engineering decks are on the other side .
JUSTIN : Kay , let 's take a look .
What the hell is this place , Dr. Weir ?
It allows you to enter the second containment
without compromising the magnetic fields .
Looks like a meat grinder to me .
PETERS : I 'm on the bridge .
Got some blood here .
( LIQUID RIPPLING )
JUSTIN : There must have been a coolant leak .
Man , this shit is everywhere .
Coolant level 's on reserve , but well within the safety line .
Miss Peters , could you turn back and left ?
STARCK : What is it ?
Ship 's log .
PETERS : It 's stuck .
It 's pretty jammed in there .
( SCREAMS )
STARCK : Oh , my God .
What the hell happened to his eyes ?
Explosive decompression .
Decompression doesn 't do that .
D.J. : Looks like it was caused by ...
I don 't know , an animal or something .
Look at the damage to the soft tissue , massive abrasions .
Corpse-sicle .
JUSTIN : I 'm scanning for life forms .
Man , I 'm getting some really strange readings in here .
Let me see if I can get some power up .
That 's the core , the gravity drive .
The heart of the ship .
( BEEPING ) Justin .
Justin , you 're breaking up .
( SCREAMING )
Justin , come in .
What is it ? I don 't know .
The life scan just went off the scale .
( BEEPING CONTINUES )
Something 's wrong , STARCK . Pull him out . Pull him out .
Oh , Shit !
( SCREAMING )
He 's in trouble .
Go , Coop . I 'm gone .
( RUMBLING )
( MILLER SCREAMING )
( GROANING )
MILLER : Boarding party , sound off .
This is Miller . Can anybody hear me ?
What the fuck was that ?
Pressure emergency ! We 've lost the starboard baffle .
The hull 's been breached !
I 'll contain it here for as long as I can ! Get out !
We 're losing atmosphere .
There are pressure suits in the airlock . Go !
COOPER : Here I come . Here I come .
Hold on , baby bear .
I 'm almost there , almost there .
I got you . I got ... ( GRUNTS )
Watch out . Watch ...
I got you . What the fuck is this ?
Hold on .
( COOPER GRUNTING )
Captain Miller . Captain Miller , do you copy ? Over .
Smitty , where you been all my life ?
We have a major situation here , sir .
We 've lost the starboard baffle , and the hull 's been breached .
Uh , the safety circuits , they have failed .
Do we have time for a weld ? No , sir .
We 've got 218 liters of gas left , sir , and then we 've got nothing .
The oxygen tanks , they failed , they 're broken .
Sir , we are fucking dead !
What about the Event Horizon ?
What ?
She 's got air and power .
It 's our only chance .
There 's no way I 'm getting on that bastard .
We don 't even know what happened on that ship .
It beats dying , Mr. Smith .
I want all personnel on board the Event Horizon , pronto .
We 'll meet at the air tanks .
I 'm ahead of you , sir . Bringing all thermal units online .
Hold tight . Prep for G 's .
Gravity in five seconds .
( BEEPING )
COOPER : Wake up , open your eyes . All right ?
Just hang in there .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
Dr. Weir .
Well ...
I brought most primary systems online
for now . Thank you .
STARCK , what 's our status ?
The antenna array is completely fried .
We 've got no radio , no laser , no high gain .
No one 's coming to help us .
This air tastes bad . Yeah , carbon dioxide , I know .
It 's building up with every breath we take .
And the 002 filters on the Event Horizon are shot .
So , we take the scrubbers from the Clark . That gives us what ?
Enough breathable air for 20 hours ,
but after that , we 'd better be on our way home .
SMITH : I 'm on the port side of the hull ,
approaching the dorsal heat sink .
Holy shit .
Captain Miller . Captain Miller , do you copy ? Over .
I copy , Mr. Smith . How 's my ship ?
Sir , we 've got a seven-meter fracture on the outer hull .
We should be able to repair her ,
but it 's gonna take an awful lot of time , sir .
Negative . 20 hours , we run out of air .
Understood , sir .
What happened here , Doctor ?
Okay , how is he ?
His vital signs seem stable , but he 's unresponsive to stimuli .
I don 't know .
He might wake up in 15 minutes .
He might not wake up at all .
Look , skipper , I know this shit sounds weird ,
but , I mean , there was like nothing ,
and then Justin appeared and " .and " .
It was liquid , and the whole core just turned solid .
It 's just not physically possible .
Doctor , please . Please , don 't start in with that physics shit .
I 'm telling you , I saw it .
Mr. Cooper , it would mean the gateway was open .
That 's it . The gateway was open .
The gateway couldn 't be open
because the gravity drive wasn 't activated .
Look , I 'm telling you what I saw , Doc ! 80 ...
( COOPER YELLING ) It can 't just start up by itself .
Mr. Cooper , you are out of line .
Doctor , Mr. Justin may die . Now , I have to assume
that whatever happened to him could happen to all of us .
Mr. Cooper says he saw something .
I believe he saw something .
I need an explanation .
In my view , Mr. Cooper 's delusional ,
if you don 't mind my saying so .
But maybe he saw
an optical effect caused by gravitational distortion .
" An optical effect " ? That 's fucking poetic .
Where the fuck ... Cooper !
I 'm sorry . All right .
Gravitational distortion .
What could create that , Doctor ?
If , somehow , a burst of gravity waves escaped from the core ,
it could distort space-time .
It could make Justin seem to disappear .
It could also have damaged the Lewis Clark .
However , I think this is entirely unlikely .
What 's in the core , Doctor ?
It 's complicated .
Well , how much time do you need ? We have
17 hours and 48 minutes .
What 's in the core ?
WEIR : This is the gateway .
Now , these three magnetic rings ,
when they align , it creates an artificial black hole
which allows the ship to travel to any point in space .
A black hole , the most destructive force in the universe .
And you 've created one ?
Absolutely , yes . Because we can
use that immense power to bend space-time .
Look , it would take the Lewis Clark 1,000 years
to reach our nearest star .
But Event Horizon could be there in a day .
If it worked .
You can come down . It 's perfectly safe .
MILLER : 80 , if Mr. Justin was sucked through your gateway ,
he could 've gone wherever the Event Horizon 's been .
WEIR : Theoretically , yes . But as I told you before ,
the gateway can 't just open by itself .
MILLER : I see .
Lieutenant , I want this room sealed off .
Second containment from here on in is off-limits .
STARCK : Yes , sir . Captain , there 's no danger .
The gateway 's contained behind three magnetic fields .
It 's perfectly safe . Safe ?
Doctor , my ship is in pieces
and one of my crewmen may not make it home alive .
No one else goes near this thing .
PETERS : Come on .
There 's got to be something on this log .
You can do this .
( FABRIC RUSTLING )
D.J. ?
D.J. , where are you ?
D.J. : I 'm up on deck four .
( FABRIC RUSTLING )
Mommy .
( EXCLAIMS ) Peters !
What is it ? You all right ?
( EXHALES )
What 's up ? You was out there so long ,
I thought you were trying to break my record .
Listen , I 'd rather spend the next 12 hours outside ,
than another five seconds in this shit can .
It 's the final entry in the ship 's log .
KILPACK : I want to say how proud I am of my crew .
I 'd like to name my station heads ,
Chris Chambers , Janice Reuben ,
Ben Fender , Dick Smith .
We 've reached safe distance ...
This is John Kilpack , ship 's captain .
And we 're preparing to engage the gravity drive ,
and open the gateway to Proxima Centauri .
( SPEAKING LATIN )
Hail and farewell .
( STATIC INTERFERENCE )
What is that ? I 'll run it through a few filters ,
see if I can clean it up .
It 's a power drain .
It 's the core .
MILLER : Stay here . Look after Justin .
I don 't want anybody else near that thing .
Wait for me , Doctor .
MILLER : What 's causing the drain ?
WEIR : Magnetic fields are holding .
Maybe a short in the fail-safe circuit . I 'll check it .
Can you give us a hand ?
( GRUNTING )
Justin .
Justin , can you hear me ?
He 's coming .
Who 's coming ?
The dark .
( SCREAMING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Ah , yeah , that 's the one .
CLAIRE : Billy .
Billy .
( WEIR BREATHING RAPIDLY )
Miller !
Captain Miller !
I 've got some problems here .
( TAPPING FLASHLIGHT )
Be with me
forever .
Dr. Weir ?
Carbon dioxide can produce hallucinations , impair judgment .
God damn it , D.J. , it was not a hallucination .
All right .
Doctor , you were in the duct .
You must have heard something .
You must have seen something .
I did .
About an hour ago , I saw my son
lying on the examination table .
And ...
And his legs were crawling ...
Miss Peters , if you don 't mind my saying so ,
it sounds a little like shock .
Could it be that you 're traumatized ...
No . No ... by seeing the body on the ...
Excuse me . No !
I 've seen bodies before . This was different .
She 's right . Now , this ... this was real .
I felt ... I felt heat .
This is not something that 's in our heads .
Smitty , have you seen anything unusual at all ?
No , I haven 't seen anything , and I don 't need to see anything , sir ,
but I can tell you ,
this ship is fucked .
Thank you for that scientific analysis , Mr. Smith .
Well , you don 't need a fucking scientist to figure it out , do you ?
All right , Doc .
When you break all the laws of physics ,
do you seriously think there won 't be a price ?
You already killed the last fucking crew .
And now you want to kill us as well !
It 's just a fucking ship , all right ? D.J. !
It 's just a ship , do you understand ?
It 's just a big hunk of metal .
There 's nothing odd going on .
D.J. ?
( PANTING )
Fine .
D.J. ?
You all right ? Yeah , I 'm just ...
I 'm sorry .
Damn it ! Smitty .
It 's all right . That 's it . Fucking ...
That 's enough ! I want you calm , I want you cool ! Now !
All right .
You 're going back upstairs .
You 're going outside on the Clark with Cooper
and you 're going to repair the ship .
No mistakes .
Mistakes , nobody goes home . Understood ?
Yes , sir . All right .
Sir . Get moving .
Miller . What is it , STARCK ?
I ran the bio-scan with the DNA-RNA filters .
The results were bio readings ...
Of an indeterminate origin . Yes , I know .
Don 't you have anything useful to tell me , Lieutenant ?
I 've got a theory .
Let 's hear it .
I think that there 's a connection between
the readings and the hallucinations ,
like , like they 're all part of a defensive reaction
some sort of immune system .
I don 't have time to listen to this .
You have to listen to me . To what ?
I 'm saying that this ship is reacting to us
and the reactions are getting stronger .
It 's as if the ship brought back something with it ,
a life force of some kind .
What are you telling me ? That this ship is alive ?
You wanted an answer , and it 's the only one I 've got .
No , what I want , Lieutenant , is to survive the next 10 hours .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
PETERS : Justin ?
Justin !
( BANGING )
( BANGING CONTINUES )
( GASPS )
Did you hear that ? Did you hear that ?
That sound . What is it ?
You heard it . What did you hear ?
What is it ? Peters , listen to me .
It 's D.J. , all right ?
I didn 't hear anything . Neither of us heard anything .
So just calm down , all right ? Okay .
Get your breath back .
Okay .
Now , tell me .
I was ... ( CRASHING )
( PETERS SCREAMING )
( BANGING )
PETERS : Make it stop ! Make it stop !
Open the door .
STARCK , move it .
No !
Weir , stop . Stop him !
STARCK : What are you doing ?
( WEIR GROANS )
In our current environment , Dr. Weir , self-control is an asset .
( GROANS )
( ALARM BLARING )
What is it ?
Um , the forward airlock .
Miller , Smith , Cooper , anyone in the airlock ?
MILLER : That 's a negative , STARCK .
Justin .
PETERS : Justin . D.J. : Don 't !
PETERS : Justin , no !
Justin , no ! Justin , open the door .
Miller , come in .
Miller , come in . We have an emergency .
What 's going on in there , STARCK ?
Justin 's in the airlock .
Say again .
Justin is in the airlock and he is not wearing a suit .
Shit . I 'm on it .
As you were , sailor .
Skipper , you need me on this .
I need you right where you are .
He 's engaged the override .
Can you shut it down ?
I 'll try .
Coming to him , STARCK .
Justin ! Open this door , now !
MILLER : STARCK , give me status .
You better hurry . He 's engaged the override
and we can 't open the inner door .
D.J. : I 'll get the kit .
Justin , open the door !
Justin , open the door .
Did you hear it ?
Keep him talking .
Yes . Yes , I heard it .
Do you know what it is ?
It shows you things horrible things .
What does ?
The dark inside me from the other place .
I won 't go back there . I won 't .
No , baby bear . Come on , open the door .
What 's happening ?
I don 't think she can talk him down .
She 'd better .
If he opens the airlock , he 's going to turn inside out .
PETERS : No . No , you stay with me .
STARCK : Almost got it .
I 've almost got it .
You stay with me , Justin .
Come on , now . Open that door !
If you could see the things I 've seen , you wouldn 't try to stop me .
No , that 's not you talking . That 's not you talking .
That 's it . That 's it , right there .
Open the door . Go for that button . Come on .
Okay , okay .
( ALARM BLARING ) No !
( SCREAMING )
Captain , Justin just activated the door .
It 's on a 30-second delay .
MILLER : Justin !
COMPUTER VOICE : Stand by for decompression in 25 seconds .
Where am I ?
JUSTIN : Hey . STARCK , get it fucking open !
Hey , open the door . I can 't .
The inner door won 't open when the outside door 's been triggered .
It would decompress the entire ship .
Oh , my God . Mama bear , open the door .
Come on , please .
JUSTIN : Captain !
Patch me through to him .
Captain Miller , tell them to open the door .
They can 't do that , Justin .
I don 't want to die in here .
You 're not gonna die .
I want you to listen to me very carefully ,
and I 'm gonna get you out of there .
Oh , my God .
It 's starting . My eyes .
Don 't think about them . Shut them .
( JUSTIN SCREAMING ) Just shut them as tight as you can .
Five seconds .
MILLER : Tuck yourself into a crouch position .
Make yourself into a ball now .
JUSTIN : I can 't breathe . Oh , God .
Oh , God , it hurts .
I want you to huff and puff and blow all the air out of your lungs .
Do you hear me ? All the air out of your lungs , Justin .
( SCREAMING )
MILLER : Do it , now !
( JUSTIN SCREAMING )
Okay , baby bear .
Got him . I got him . Standby , people .
Standby .
( JUSTIN CHOKING )
We 've got pressure .
PETERS : We 're coming , Justin . We 're coming .
I 'm going to need five units here .
Hold his head still .
PETERS : Okay .
( COUGHING )
Give me some more mysoline , now .
One thing at a time , let 's keep him breathing .
PETERS : He 's bleeding out . Pressure 's still dropping . Start the drip , 15 cc .
I 've stopped the bleeding , stabilized him best I can .
( SIGHING )
He won 't be pretty , but he should live ,
if we make it back . We 'll make it .
STARCK , what 's our time like ?
002 levels will become toxic in four hours .
All right .
Peters , we 've got to find out what happened to the other crew
before the same thing happens to us .
Well , I can work on the log on the bridge ,
but I won 't go back to medical .
Fine .
Yes , sir .
Justin said something about
" the dark inside me . "
What 's that mean ?
Doctor ?
I don 't think it means anything .
MILLER : Don 't you walk away from me , Mister .
I 'd like some answers , Doctor .
I 'd like to know why one of my men tried to commit suicide
by throwing himself out of an airlock .
I 'd like to know what caused that noise .
Look , thermal changes in the hull
could 've caused the metal to expand and contract rapidly
causing reverberations . This is possible .
Bullshit ! You built this fucking ship .
You 've given me nothing but bullshit .
What do you want me to say ?
You said the ship 's drive creates a gateway .
Yeah . To what ?
I don 't know . Where did it go ?
Where did you send it ? I don 't know .
Where has it been for the last seven years ?
Look , I don 't know .
" I don 't know , " is not good enough , Doctor .
You 're supposed to be the fucking expert .
I need answers . That 's your job .
Now , the other place , where is that ?
I don 't know ! I don 't know !
Look ,
there 's a lot of things happening around here that I don 't fully understand .
( STUTTERING ) I need time .
I see .
Well , that 's exactly what we don 't have , Doctor .
CORRICK : Captain !
Don 't leave me !
Please !
For God 's sakes , help me !
( EXHALES )
It 's in your head .
It 's just in your head .
God help us .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
MILLER : I 'm telling you , it was his voice I heard .
He was calling to me .
A young bosun named Eddie Corrick .
We served on the Goliath together .
When the 02 tanks ruptured , four of us made it to the lifeboat .
But Corrick was still on board the Goliath
when the fire broke out .
You ever seen fire in zero gravity ?
It 's beautiful .
It 's like liquid .
It slides all over everything .
Comes up in waves .
And they just kept hitting him ,
wave after wave .
He was screaming for me to save him .
What did you do ?
I did the only thing I could .
I closed the lifeboat hatch , and I left him behind .
I swore I 'd never lose another man .
I 've known you a long time .
You never told me that .
That 's just it , D.J. , I ... I never told anybody .
But this ship knew about it .
It knows my fears . It knows my secrets .
Gets inside your head , and it shows you .
I wasn 't going to tell you this .
I 've been listening to the distress signal .
And I , um ...
I think I made a mistake in the translation .
( MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
( SIGHS )
Go on .
I thought it said " liberate me . "
" Save me . "
But it 's not " me . "
It 's " liberate tutu me . "
" Save yourself . "
And it gets worse .
( MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
There .
I think
that says " ex inferis . "
" Save yourself
" from hell . "
Look , if what Dr. Weir tells us is true ,
this ship has been beyond the boundaries of our universe ,
of known scientific reality .
Who knows where it 's been ,
what it 's seen ,
and what it 's brought back with it ?
From hell .
You don 't believe in that kind of stuff , do you ?
Whoever sent that message , he sure believes in hell .
COOPER : Captain Miller .
Whatever it is , Coop , it better be good .
COOPER : Yes , sir .
Ready to repressurize the Clark and get the hell out of here .
On my way .
MILLER : Come on , baby , don 't let me down .
Hello , baby . Papa 's home .
SMITH : She 's holding .
Oh , Shit .
COOPER : Skipper , we 're still venting trace gasses .
Give me about 20 minutes to plug the hole .
MILLER : Cooper , you are the lifesaver .
20 minutes and we 're underway .
Shit .
Got any coffee ?
Yeah , but it 's cold .
Great .
( PEOPLE SCREAMING )
STARCK .
Miller ?
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
( PEOPLE SCREAMING )
( SPEAKING LATIN )
We 're leaving .
No , we can 't leave .
Our orders are specific .
Rescue the crew , salvage what 's left of the ship .
The crew is dead , Doctor .
Your ship killed them .
We came here to do a job .
We 're aborting , Doctor !
STARCK , download the files from the Event Horizon 's computers .
D.J. , I want you to get Justin
prepped and ready to move him back to the Clark .
There 's stuff I wanna get from medical .
We 'd better move him in the tank . No problem . Do it .
Peters . Yes , sir .
I want you to get the CO2 scrubbers back into the Clark .
Take Smitty with you . Right .
WEIR : Captain .
Captain .
Don 't do this .
It 's done .
What about my ship ? You can 't just leave her .
I have no intention of leaving her , Doctor .
I will take the Lewis Clark to a safe distance
and then I will launch tac missiles at the Event Horizon
until I 'm satisfied she 's vaporized . Fuck this ship .
( GRUNTING )
( ALARM BEEPING )
Captain Miller , the bio-scan just went off the scale .
It looks like the core
is draining power from the rest of the ship .
Get the files . Vacate .
I want off this ship .
You can 't leave . She won 't let you .
You just get your gear and get back on the Lewis Clark , Doctor
or you 'll find yourself walkin ' home .
I am home .
PETERS : Let 's go !
Ready ?
D.J. : Shot .
PETERS : Come on . Come on .
Ready ? Shot .
Shot Okay .
Peters , can we go ? This place is really freaking me out .
Yeah , you wanna breathe on the way home .
No , I don 't ! Let 's go !
Shit !
25 . Come on !
We need 25 . Peters !
Come on ! Got it !
( BANGING )
( BANGING CONTINUES )
( PANTING )
( SCREAMING )
Oh , no . Peters .
Oh , God .
CLAIRE : Billy .
Claire ?
Claire .
It 's me . I 'm home .
I 'm home .
I know I wasn 't there when you needed me ,
and I 'm sorry I ...
I let my work come between us .
God , Claire , no .
I 'm begging you , please . Please , don 't .
Not again , please .
I 've been so ...
CLAIRE : Billy .
It 's all right .
I 've been so alone .
You 'll never be alone again .
You 're with me now . You 're with me
and I have such wonderful , wonderful things
to show you .
( SCREAMING )
Damn , I 'm good .
Coop .
Coop , how long are you going to take ?
' Cause I 've got to get the hell out of here .
Look , you can kiss my ass , Smith , ' cause I 'm done .
Just give me a second to collect my tools
and we can get out of dodge .
Two minutes tops .
Roger that .
( BANGING )
SMITH : Weir .
Dr. Weir .
Weir !
Dr. Weir , get your ass back on board now !
Shit .
Captain Miller , captain Miller , do you copy ? Over .
Captain Miller . Captain Miller , do you copy ? Over .
Go ahead , Smitty .
I 've just seen Weir messing around on the Clark , sir .
Standby , Smitty , I wanna check something out .
Smith , get out of there .
Come again , sir ?
One of the explosives is missing from the corridor .
Weir might have put it on the Clark .
No . No way .
No , no , sir , no way .
I 've just put it back together , sir .
Get off the Clark now , Smith !
Where the fucking hell are you ?
Got you .
MILLER : Hang on , Smitty . I 'm coming !
( BEEPING )
( SHUDDERING )
No !
Shit !
COOPER : Shit !
Where the fuck am I going ?
Why does this shit got to happen to me ?
Fuck .
All right , think , Coop . Think . Think .
All right , all right , I got to get back to the ship .
I got to get back to the ship , all right .
I gotta blow my air tank .
I 'll blow my air tank .
( HISSING )
All right . Fuck .
This better work . This shit better work .
All right . Here I go . All right .
( BEEPING ) One , two , three . Come on .
Come on , come on , come on .
Yes ! Yes ! Yes !
Here I come , motherfuckers !
D.J.
What was that ?
Clark 's gone .
Smitty and Cooper are dead .
What ? What the ...
It was Weir . You spot him , you take him out .
Understood .
Be careful , D.J.
Don 't worry about Weir .
I 'll take care of him .
( CHOKING )
D.J. ?
( GRUNTING )
( SCREAMING )
MILLER : D.J. ? D.J. , answer me !
( KNIFE CUTTING )
( GROANING )
MILLER : Okay , Dr. Weir .
( COCKING GUN ) You don 't wanna leave your ship ?
You never will .
( THUNDER CLAPPING )
STARCK .
It 's okay .
I 'm gonna get you out of here .
Okay .
Easy .
Oh , my God .
What happened to your eyes ?
Where we 're going , we won 't need eyes to see .
What are you talking about ?
I created the Event Horizon to reach the stars .
But she 's gone much , much farther than that .
She tore a hole in our universe ,
a gateway to another dimension .
A dimension of pure chaos ,
pure evil .
When she crossed over , she was just a ship .
But when she came back ,
she was alive .
Look at her , Miller .
Isn 't she beautiful ?
Your beautiful ship killed its crew , Doctor .
Well ,
now she has another crew .
Now she has us .
What do you think you 're doing , Doctor ?
You wanted to know where the ship has been ,
so now you 'll find out .
( GRUNTING )
If you miss me , you blow out the hull .
What makes you think I 'll miss ?
COOPER : That 's right , I 'm back !
I 'm ... Oh , shit , I can 't stop . Hey !
Hey ! Fuck .
( GRUNTING )
What ? Who the fuck ? Oh , Shit !
( SCREAMING )
( YELLING )
Miller !
( GRUNTING )
( WEIR SCREAMING )
Miller ! Miller !
( ALARM BLARING )
Give me your hand !
( GRUNTING )
MILLER : Come on !
I can 't !
I 'm not leaving you .
( ALARM BLARING )
Forward airlock .
It can 't be Weir .
I 'm not taking any chances .
You watch your back .
Yo ! Don 't hit me .
STARCK : Cooper !
Take it off ! Take it off !
I can 't breathe . I can 't breathe .
You 're okay . You 're okay . It 's over .
No , it 's not .
Weir 's activated the gravity drive .
We gotta shut it down .
How ? The bridge is gone . What about engineering ?
You think you can shut it down from there ?
I don 't know the process . Dr. Weir was the expert .
I don 't want to go where the other crew went , okay ?
I 'd rather be dead .
Okay . Okay , we blow the fucker up .
We blow it up ?
Do like Weir said . Blow the corridor ,
separate us from the rest of ship .
Use the foredecks as a lifeboat .
With any luck , TDRS will pick up our emergency beacon .
We prep the gravity couches , put ourselves in stasis
and standby for a search and rescue team .
Meantime , I 'm gonna go manually arm these explosives .
Skipper , will this shit work ?
It worked for Dr. Weir . You go activate the emergency beacon .
You get back here double-quick .
Yes , sir . I 'll come with you .
You stay here . You prep the gravity couches .
Miller .
Close this door behind me , Lieutenant .
COMPUTER VOICE : Gateway opening in T minus five minutes .
Emergency beacon activated .
Yes .
Blood ?
Oh , fuck me .
Fuck me .
STARCK !
( SCREAMING )
Run !
COMPUTER VOICE : Gateway opening in T minus three minutes .
Detonator release is authorized .
The main corridor is now armed .
We 're armed . She 's ready to blow .
I repeat , we are armed . She 's ready to blow .
Miller . Miller , can you hear me ?
We have to get out of here now .
( FIRE RUMBLING )
You let me burn .
COMPUTER VOICE : Gateway opening in T minus two minutes .
CORRICK : Miller .
( MILLER SCREAMING )
( MILLER COUGHING )
CORRICK : You left me behind .
No , you 're not Edmund Corrick .
I watched him die .
Weir ?
( CHUCKLING )
The ship brought me back .
I told you she won 't let me leave .
She won 't let anyone leave .
Did you really think you could destroy this ship ?
She 's defied space and time .
She 's been to a place you couldn 't possibly imagine .
And now
it is time to go back .
I know , to hell .
You know nothing . Hell is only a word .
The reality is much , much worse .
Now let me show you .
Help me !
( SCREAMING )
No !
No .
You see ?
They 're not dead . They 're not dead .
Not yet .
( YELLING )
You won 't take my crew .
( SCREAMING )
( MILLER GRUNTING )
They 're not your crew anymore .
They belong to the ship .
COMPUTER VOICE : Gateway opening .
( GROANING )
( SCREAMS )
MILLER : Take me .
You take me . You leave them alone .
No . There is no escape .
The gateway is open
and you are all coming with me .
Do you see ?
Yes ,
I see .
No !
( EXPLOSION )
Miller .
MAN : This is rescue one . We have contact .
Approaching the wreckage of the Event Horizon .
Prepare to board .
I 'm entering the grav couch bay .
It doesn 't appear to have been damaged in the explosion .
There appear to be three survivors ,
Cooper , Justin , Lieutenant STARCK .
Justin seems to have suffered massive injuries
but he 's still alive .
The grav couches still have power .
I 'm opening the first tank now .
( GASPING )
It 's all right . It 's okay .
You 're safe now .
Justin , Cooper .
They 're fine . They 're with us .
They 're with us .
( SCREAMING )
COOPER : STARCK . STARCK .
Stay calm . It 's all right .
Calm down , it 's me .
Breathe deeply .
STARCK . Breath deeply .
It 's the rescue team . I need a sedative here , now !
I got you , STARCK . I got you .
It 's okay .
I need a sedative here , now !
STARCK , it 's the rescue team . We 're safe .
Okay , okay , I need it now !
COOPER : We 're safe .
( ROCK MUSIC PLAYING )